crossmediaservices.com 2010-01-13

# ShopLocal, the leader in multi-channel shopping services, connects advertisers and consumers.

  | 

ShopLocal.com™ embraces the privacy guidelines as developed by the Online Privacy Alliance (OPA) and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), and this privacy policy adheres to the principles addressed in those guidelines. To view these guidelines, please visit the web sites of the corresponding organization, <http://www.privacyalliance.org/resources/ppguidelines.shtml> and <http://www.ftc.gov/reports/privacy3/fairinfo.htm>.

**P3P**  
ShopLocal.com™ is in compliance with the current draft of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) Platform for Privacy Preferences (P3P) specification, http://www.w3c.org/P3P, dated April 16, 2002. This specification was developed to allow users to more easily evaluate the use of personal information collected by the web sites they visit. Thus, if your browser is Microsoft Internet Explorer Version 6, or later, your browser can electronically interpret the P3P version of our privacy policies. 

**Collection and use of non-personal information**  
If you visit ShopLocal.com™, we do not collect any personally identifiable information about you (such as your name, address, phone number or email address) unless you provide it. We do, however, collect non-personally-identifiable (anonymous) information about you, such as the server your computer is logged into or your browser type. Other examples of non-personally-identifiable information include: 

  * Your IP address (a unique number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web; many Web servers automatically identify your computer by its IP address). 
  * Your domain type (i.e., .com, .net, .edu, etc.). 
  * Standard information included with every communication sent on the Internet, such as browser type, operating system, browser language, service provider, and local time. 

ShopLocal.com™ collects data from the Web logs of its servers -- the computers that “serve up” Web pages -- delivering the ShopLocal.com™ content. This includes information about what you view and, along with information gathered from our other users, we create “aggregate data” reports that we may disclose to third parties, including our clients with whom we have entered into an agreement to provide such information. We may also study aggregate data in order to enhance our existing services or develop new services. We will not disclose any personal information to a third party without your express prior written authorization. We can and will use IP addresses to identify a user when we feel it is necessary to enforce compliance with our or terms of use or to protect our service, site, customers, or others. 

**Use of cookies**  
ShopLocal.com™ uses cookies on our web site. Cookies are used for record keeping, to track your movements when you visit a Web site and to help us determine what type of information to present to you. The use of cookies is an industry standard - you’ll find them used at most Web sites. Our cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information about you, and do not damage or alter your system files in any way. The first time you visit our web site, ShopLocal.com™ assigns you a unique, anonymous, ID, which is stored in the cookie on your computer. 

**Collection of personal information**  
ShopLocal.com™ requests location information in order to create a personalized Shopping Zone for you. A Shopping Zone allows us to determine which sales and deals are available at stores near you. When providing location information, you may enter a city and State or a Zip Code. If you choose to register for Email Alerts, we do require your email address. We will not share any of this information with any third party unless you explicitly ask us to. The Email Alerts feature offers the opportunity to receive email regarding special offers from ShopLocal.com™. If you request this information, we will send the appropriate information to the email address you provide. If you don’t request this information, we won’t send it to you. ShopLocal.com™ does not share any contact information with third parties. Users, both registered and unregistered, may opt to use a feature on ShopLocal.com™ called “Share This Page.” This site feature allows the user to notify someone, via email, about a deal found on ShopLocal.com™. Use of this feature requires the user to enter the email address to which this information will be sent. Email addresses entered through the Share This Page feature will not be used for any other purpose. 

**Who is collecting your information**  
Your information is being collected solely by CrossMedia Services, Inc., the owner and operator of ShopLocal.com™. See the discussion under “With whom your information may be shared” below concerning the circumstances under which certain of your information may be disclosed to third parties. 

**With whom your information may be shared**  
ShopLocal.com™ does not sell trade or rent your personal information to others. As discussed above under “Collection and use of non-personal information,” we may provide aggregate statistics about our users, traffic patterns and related site information to our clients or for other marketing and promotional purposes. In these situations, we would not disclose any information that could be used to personally identify you. 

**Retention of information**  
Any information we collect may be retained for an indeterminate period of time. 

**Confidentiality and Security**  
ShopLocal.com™ has implemented generally accepted standards of technology security in order to protect information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction. Only employees of CrossMedia Services, Inc. have access to the information we collect, and these employees are made aware of and required to comply with our privacy policy. 

**Links to Other Sites**  
ShopLocal.com™ may provide links to an external Web site. When you click on such a link, you will leave ShopLocal.com™. The privacy policy of the external Web site will then be in effect, not ShopLocal’s. ShopLocal.com™ does not control or makes an endorsement of any kind regarding the external site or its privacy policy. ShopLocal’s policy does not extend to anything that is inherent in the operation of the Internet, and therefore beyond ShopLocal’s control, and is not to be applied in any manner contrary to applicable law or governmental regulation. We do not control cookies from the other sites that you may link to from ShopLocal. 

**Children**  
ShopLocal.com™ is not a commercial Web site or an online service directed to children under 13 years of age and our content and other services are not written, intended, or designed for children under the age of 13. To ensure that CrossMedia Services, Inc. stays in compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), we review the details of COPPA on a regular basis. 

**Changes to this privacy policy**  
All versions of this privacy policy are dated with the effective date (the date on which the policy was posted to ShopLocal.com™). ShopLocal.com™ will only use the information we learn about you in the manner described in the Privacy Policy in effect when the information was collected from you. However, we reserve the right to change the terms of this Privacy Policy at any time by posting revisions to our site. 

**Changes in corporate structure**  
If ShopLocal.com™ is sold, merged or otherwise transferred to another entity, the personal information you have provided at this site may be transferred as part of that transaction. However, ShopLocal.com™ will take steps to assure that any personal information is used in a manner consistent with the ShopLocal.com™ privacy policy under which it was collected. 

**Effect of Legal Obligations upon this Privacy Policy**  
ShopLocal.com™ may disclose user information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) ShopLocal’s rights or property, other ShopLocal.com™ users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. ShopLocal.com™ may disclose user information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it. 

**Effect of Privacy Policy**  
This privacy policy is not intended to and does not create any contractual or legal rights in or on behalf of any party. As noted above, we may revise this privacy policy from time to time in our sole discretion. 

**Questions**  
If you have questions about this privacy policy, please contact us at privacy@ShopLocal.com™.
